{"Topic": "Rivers, Cities and Dams", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following dams is not on the River Krishna?", "op1": "Nagar junasagar", "op2": "Krishnaraja Sagar", "op3": "Srisailam", "op4": "Alamatti", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match the following :", "op1": "A - 4; B - 3; C - 1; D - 2", "op2": "A - 4; B - 3; C - 2; D - 1", "op3": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 3; D - 4", "op4": "A - 1; B - 2; C - 4; D - 3", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The city located on the banks of Gomati is", "op1": "Kanpur", "op2": "Allahabad", "op3": "Lucknow", "op4": "Ghaziabad", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Tehri Dam of Uttarakhand has been constructed on the river -", "op1": "Teesta", "op2": "Alaknanda", "op3": "Bhagirathi", "op4": "Ghaggar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Chutak Hydro-electric project being constructed by NHPC in Kargil is on the river -", "op1": "Suru", "op2": "Jhelum", "op3": "Kunar", "op4": "Ravi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "On the banks of which of the following rivers is Srinagar located?", "op1": "Sutlej", "op2": "Indus", "op3": "Ravi", "op4": "Jhelum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Maithon Dam, which was in news during the 34th National Games is located on which of the following rivers?", "op1": "Damodar", "op2": "Barakar", "op3": "Hooghly", "op4": "Padma", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Nimoo Bazgo hydro-electric Project being constructed by NHPC in Leh is located on river -", "op1": "Indus", "op2": "Beas", "op3": "Ravi", "op4": "Chenab", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following pair is not correctly matched?", "op1": "Kota - Chambal", "op2": "Bhubaneswar - Mahanadi", "op3": "Jabalpur - Narmada", "op4": "Surat - Tapti", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "On which of the following rivers is Ukai dam located?", "op1": "Chenab", "op2": "Narmada", "op3": "Beas", "op4": "Tapti", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following cities is not located on the banks of Ganga ?", "op1": "Kanpur", "op2": "Patna", "op3": "Agra", "op4": "Varanasi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following dams is located on the river Ravi?", "op1": "Pong", "op2": "Thein", "op3": "Ukai", "op4": "Baglihar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Consider the following statements:", "op1": "1 and 2", "op2": "3 only", "op3": "2 and 3", "op4": "1 and 3", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "ch of the statements given above is/are correct?", "op1": "Narmada", "op2": "Kaveri", "op3": "Tapti", "op4": "Periyar"}, {"Question": "Hirakud dam, one of the longest dams (length \u2013 25.8 km) in the world is located on river -", "op1": "Godavari", "op2": "Tungabhadra", "op3": "Mahanadi", "op4": "Brahmaputra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is wrongly matched?", "op1": "Hirakud  : Mahanadi", "op2": "Nagarjuna Sagar  : Cauvery", "op3": "Bhakra Nangal  :Sutlej", "op4": "Pochamped  : Godavari", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following dams is also known as Maharana Pratap Sagar?", "op1": "Ukai Dam", "op2": "Pong Dam", "op3": "Thein Dam", "op4": "Koyna Dam", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Raighat dam is situated on river :", "op1": "Nanmada", "op2": "Sutlej", "op3": "Betwa", "op4": "Chambal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "On which of the following rivers is Gandhisagar Dam located?", "op1": "Son", "op2": "Betwa", "op3": "Chambal", "op4": "Sabarmati", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "On which river is the Bhakra Nangal Dam located", "op1": "Sutlej", "op2": "Ravi", "op3": "Chenab", "op4": "Beas", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following cities is located on the banks of the River Saryu?", "op1": "Varanasi", "op2": "Ayodhya", "op3": "Kanpur", "op4": "Allahabad", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "On which river has \u2018Naranarayan Setu\u2019 been built?", "op1": "Ganga", "op2": "Brahmaputra", "op3": "Mahanadi", "op4": "Godavari", "Answer": 2}]}